Transcript and translation
from April Fisher http://youtu.be/vx-SCOBktzc
Sung by Sia Koskina (Σία Κοσκινά)
The snow glows white on the mountain tonight,
Το χιόνι αγκαλιάζει το βουνό
To chióni agkaliázei to voynó
The snow embraces the mountain
not a footprint to be seen
Δίχως ίχνη, δίχως φωνή
Díchōs íchnī, díchōs fōnī́
Without a trace, without a voice
A kingdom of isolation,
Βασίλισσα σ῾ ένα θρόνο
Vasílissa sh éna thróno
Queen in a throne
and it looks like I'm the queen
από πάγο και σιωπή
apó págo kai siōpī́
of ice and silence
The wind is howling like this swirling storm inside
Είναι η σιωπή π῾ ουρλιάζει πόνο αναζητά
Eínai ī siōpī́ ph oyrliázei póno anazītá
It's the silence that's screaming, looking for pain
Couldn't keep it in, heaven knows I tried
Πώς να κρατηθεί μέσα μου βαθειά?
Pṓs na kratītheí mésa moy vatheiá?
How can it be kept deep inside of me?
Don't let them in, don't let them see
Κανείς να μην υποψιαστεί
Kaneís na mīn ypopsiasteí
No one must suspect
Be the good girl you always had to be
Θα ῾μαι η καλή που ξέρουν μια ζωή
Tha hmai ī kalī́ poy xéroyn mia zōī́
I'll be the good one they've known all their lives
Conceal, don't feel, don't let them know
Να μη χαθει το μυστικό...!
Na mī chathei to mystikó...!
The secret must not get lost...!
Well, now they know!
Μα είναι γνωστό!
Ma eínai gnōstó!
But (now) it's known!
Let it go, let it go!
Και ξεχνώ, τα ξεχνώ
Kai xechnṓ, ta xechnṓ
And I forget, I forget
Can't hold it back any more!
Και πίςω δεν κοιτώ
Kai písō den koitṓ
And I'm not looking back
Let it go, let it go!
Τα ξεχνώ, προχωρώ
Ta xechnṓ, prochōrṓ
I forget, I move on
Turn away and slam the door!
Τη ζωή μου ξεκινώ!
Tī zōī́ moy xekinṓ!
I start my life!
I don't care what they're going to say
Φτάνει πια! Κό βω σκοινί!
Ftánei pia! Kó vō skoiní!
That's enough! I cut the cord!
Let the storm rage on
Κι ας παγώνει η γη...
Ki as pagṓnei ī gī...
And let the earth freeze...
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Το κρύο την καρδιά μου δεν τηυ ενοχλεί.
To krýo tīn kardiá moy den tīy enochleí.
The cold doesn't bother my heart.
It's funny how some distance
Ετην απεραντοδύνη,
Etīn aperantodýnī,
In the infinity,
Makes everything seem small
όλα φαίνονται μικρά
óla faínontai mikrá
everything seems small
And the fears that once controlled me
Τωρα οι φόβοι κι οι ενοχές μου
Tōra oi fóvoi ki oi enochés moy
Now my fears and my guilt
Can't get to me at all!
δε μ῾ εξουσιάζουν πια!
de mh exoysiázoyn pia!
don't control me any more!
It's time to see what I can do
Καιρός να μάθω τι μπορώ!
Kairós na máthō ti mporṓ!
It's time to find out what I can do!
To test the limits and break through
Τα όριά μου εγώ τα ξεπερνώ!
Ta óriá moy egṓ ta xepernṓ!
I surpass my limits!
No right, no wrong, no rules for me
Αν βγω απ῾ αυτή τη φυλακή...
An vgō aph aytī́ tī fylakī́...
If I escape from this prison...
I'm free!
Μου αρκεί...!
Moy arkeí...!
That's enough for me!
Let it go, let it go!
Και ξεχνώ, τα ξεχνώ
Kai xechnṓ, ta xechnṓ
And I forget, I forget
I am one with the wind and sky
Γίνομαι ένα με τον ουρανό
Gínomai éna me ton oyranó
I become one with the sky
Let it go, let it go!
Και ξεχνώ, τα ξεχνώ
Kai xechnṓ, ta xechnṓ
And I forget, I forget
You'll never see me cry
Το δάκρυ συγκρατώ!
To dákry sygkratṓ!
I hold back my tears!
Here I stand, and here I'll stay,
Ελεύθερη!
Eleýtherī!
(I am) free!
Let the storm rage on...
Ας παγώσει η γη...
As pagṓsei ī gī...
Let the earth freeze...
My power flurries through the air and to the ground
Η δύναμή μου σκίζει πέφτοντας τη γη...
Ī dýnamī́ moy skízei péftontas tī gī...
My power splits the earth as it falls...
My soul is spiralling in frozen fractals all around
Ψυχή που αναβλύζει σα γλυκού νερού πηγή...
Psychī́ poy anavlýzei sa glykoý neroý pīgī́...
A soul that's streaming like a freshwater spring...
And one thought crystallizes like an icy blast
Σαν έκρηξη μια σκέψη λιώνει τα βουνά!
San ékrīxī mia sképsī liṓnei ta voyná!
Like an explosion, a thought melts the mountains!
I'm never going back
Θολό μου παρελθόν
Tholó moy parelthón
My blurry past
The past is in the past!
Τα λέμε, άντε γεια!
Ta léme, ánte geia!
(See you) Later, goodbye!
Let it go, let it go!
Και ξεχνώ! Και ξεχνώ!
Kai xechnṓ! Kai xechnṓ!
And I forget! And I forget!
And I'll rise like the break of dawn
Στα παλιά πίσω δε γυρνώ!
Sta paliá písō de gyrnṓ!
I'm not going back!
Let it go, let it go!
Τα ξεχνω! Χαιρετώ...
Ta xechnō! Chairetṓ...
I forget! I greet...
That perfect girl is gone
... το νέο μου εαυτό!
... to néo moy eaytó!
... my new self!
Here I stand in the light of day
Ζωντανή! Σαν ανατολή!
Zōntanī́! San anatolī́!
(I'm) alive! Like the break of dawn!
Let the storm rage on!
ΚΙ ΑΣ ΠΑΓΏΣΕΙ Η ΓΗ!
KI AS PAGṒSEI Ī GĪ!
AND LET THE EARTH FREEZE!
The cold never bothered me anyway.
Το κρύο την καρδιά μου δεν την ενοχλεί.
To krýo tīn kardiá moy den tīn enochleí.
The cold doesn't bother my heart.